بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ

3D Quran Network

3D Quran Network project is a 3D visualization of the internal structure of the Quran's Text
as an undirected graph network with nodes and links connecting words with same text, root, or value
with support for pan/tilt/zoom/flythrough.

The Quran contains ~78,000 words with ~12,000,000 links connecting similar words by text, root, or value.
Obviously, connecting ALL similar words together would yield a very crowded and noisy network.
Therefore, 3D Quran Network will only connect similar words from longest to shortest repeated word range.

Quran's Text Properties
  - The Quran uses 29 Arabic alphabets.
  - There are 77878 words (14637 unique words).
  - Word length = 1 to 11 letters.
  - Longest repeated word range = 26 words in 4 verses (23:5-8 <-> 70:29-32).
  - Most repeated word range = 4 words in 31 verses in a single chapter (55).

Graph Properties
  - x-axis = chapter number.     [1 to 114]
  - y-axis = verses per chapter. [3 to 286]
  - z-axis = words per verse.    [1 to 128]

NODE (x,y,z) is drawn as a sphere with a diameter of 1 to 11 pixels depending on its number of letters.

LINK (x1,y1,z1 <-> x2,y2,z2) contains 1 to 11 SUBLINKs based on word length.

SUBLINK has one of 29 colors depending on its letter in the Arabic alphabet.

Graph Analysis
3D Quran Network may reveal a schematic design for a time-travel machine !
يَٰمَعْشَرَ ٱلْجِنِّ وَٱلْإِنسِ إِنِ ٱسْتَطَعْتُمْ أَن تَنفُذُوا۟ مِنْ أَقْطَارِ ٱلسَّمَٰوَٰتِ وَٱلْأَرْضِ فَٱنفُذُوا۟ ۚ لَا تَنفُذُونَ إِلَّا بِسُلْطَٰنٍۢ
055:033 O company of jinn and humans! If you wish to pass through the confines of the heavens and the earth, then try to pass through. You will not pass through except by an authority [from God].

God knows all,

Ali Adams
qurancode.com
God > ∞
