QuranCode1433 Standard/Research/Ultimate/BigNumber Editions

► Ctrl+Click a word to display verses with related words from the same root.
► Calculate and display the values of selected text/selection/Book in all numerical systems at once.
► Full statistics of the word Allah and its derivatives (2816 in total).
► Updated root database by Ali Adams and Yudi Rohmad (Indonesia).
► Easy selection of initialized chapters (الحروف المقطعة) and non-initialized chapters.
► Auto display of 4n+1 Prime = Sum and difference of two squares.
► Auto display of 4n+1 Composite = Difference of two squares in two ways.
► Front-Back Symmetry (WordLetters, VerseWords, VerseLetters).
► Waleed's CPIndexChain System. See QuranCode\Help\114.txt Pattern 619.
► Full information for Allah, non-Allah, repeated, and all Quran words
► Display number of verses before and after current verse within its chapter and within the whole Quran.
► C, V, C+V, C-V classification into Odd/Even and Prime-composite for current chapters.
► C, V, C+V, C-V classification into Odd/Even and Prime-composite for current verses.
► Calculate the LetterFrequencySum for any user phrase in each verse in all selected chapters.
► Visual representation of found matches per chapter using different color shades.
► Highlight of values that are divisible by any user-defined divisor.
► Support for IndoPak font family (thanks to brother Tariq Mahmood, Pakistan).
► Waw as a word option in any Simplified text mode.
► Shadda as a double letter option in any Simplified text mode.
► BismAllah chapter prefixes option in any Simplified text mode. BismAllah of surat Al-Fatiha is not a prefix but verse #1.
► Multi-select in Word Frequency List sorted in descending order.
► Multi-select in Letter Frequency List with immediate sum prime factorization.
► Assign DNA symbols (A T C G) to the Arabic alphabet in prime number proportions (Belkacem Meghzouchene, Algeria).
► Ratio-based colorization at letter/word/sentence/verse/chapter boundaries with both (1 + r) and (r + 1) directions. Default is the golden ratio.
► Find sentences by numbers (words/letters/value).
► Find sentences by letter frequency sum.
► Verse translations in all selected languages are displayed at the same time.
► Display Original text but use Simplified29 word/letter counts.
► Display chapter detailed info as you move over each chapter.
► Calculate any mathematical including + - * / ^ pi e phi sin cos log ... (in number bases 2 to 36).
► Improved search in emlaaei to find hamza + elf = elf memdooda (thanks to Ali Pouradam).
► FindByNumbers words / sentences / verses / chapters by numbers, words, letters, unique letters, value, or their sums.
► FindByNumbers word ranges / verse ranges / chapter ranges by sum of numbers, chapters, verses, words, letters, unique letters, value, or their sums.
► FindByNumbers word sets / verse sets / chapter sets by sum of numbers, chapters, verses, words, letters, unique letters, value, or their sums.
► FindByNumbers supports all comparison operators and MultipleOf N and IndivisibleBy N (with user-defined remainder).
► F1  = Help
► F2  = Bookmarks
► F3/Shift+F3 = navigate forward/backward through search results.
► F4  = Related Words as current selected text or word under mouse pointer.
► F5  = Related Verses as current verse under mouse pointer.
► F6  = Similar Verses as current verse under mouse pointer.
► F7  = Same Text as current selected text or word under mouse pointer.
► F8  = Same Harakat as current selected text or word under mouse pointer.
► F9 = Same Value as current selected text or verse under mouse pointer.
► Play Previous verse and Play Next verse buttons added to mp3 player.
► Dynamic keyboard for each text mode with optional harakat inclusion.
► Optional addition of L, W, V, C, ∆L, ∆W, ∆V, ∆C to the total value.
► Optional addition of W, V, C, ∆W, ∆V, ∆C to the total value.
► Optional addition of V, C, ∆V, ∆C to the total value.
► Optional addition of C to the total value.
► Search in current translation or in all currently installed translations.
► Search in current text mode or in all text modes in case user enters non-simplified letters in a simplified text mode.
► Search by root with multi-root support and +/- include/exclude options.
► Find by Frequency supports all comparison operators.
► WORDS search supports "-" and "+" at word start to exclude or include words respectively.
► Silence between verses from 0.0 to 2.0 times the verse length in 0.1 increments.
► Draw the locations of the word "Allah" in the current selection.
► Draw selection letter/word values as square, golden ratios, or spirals.
► Sort chapters by number, name, revelation, verses, words, letters, or value.
► Direct chapter/verse entry (1, 3-4, 5:55, 3-4:19, 6:19-23, 24:35-27:62).
► Direct page, station, part, group, half, quarter, bowing, verse, word, letter entry (1, 1-2, ...).
► Word grammar in Arabic and English adapted from https://corpus.quran.com
► Chapter/Verse/Word/Letter distances on text clicks across pages or across search results.
► Word meaning and transliteration as mouse moves over words.
► Auto-download recitations in any reciter from https://everyayah.com with auto-repeat 2, 3, 5, 7 or unlimited times.
► Auto-download translations from https://tanzil.net
► Auto-detect search language (Arabic or any loaded translation).
► Back/Shift+Back to move backward/forward in browse or find history.
► Find History and Browse History (with auto-select chapter range).
► Add, remove, edit and auto-save/auto-load Bookmark notes.
► Support for base 2-36 number systems (to study base-19).
► Support for any user defined SimplifiedXX Quran books.
► Any-language search in Uthmani, Emlaei, Turkish, Farsi, Urdu, Malay, Indonesian, English, Polish, Japanese, Russian, Chinese, ...

Additional Tools
► QuranNet for generating a 3D graph network of all Quran words (widest word-span first).
► QuranLab for investigating the amazing properties of the 114 number of verses per chapter in the Quran.
► InitialLetters to form sentences using the 14 Quran's initial letters (Hiroof Muqata3a) and Quran words only.
► Prime Calculator with built-in Yafu tool for factoring big numbers with next/previous prime finder.
► Calculator with missing parameter calculations for circle/sphere/triangle.
► Composites for finding composites with specified number of factors and analyze their types.

God bless and protect those who follow His Commandments.

Ali Adams
qurancode.com
God > ∞
