What is Islam?

Islam is the submission to the rules set by our Creator, God.

Allah is His name in Arabic as used by Jews, Christians and Muslimes alike.

He created our souls at the same time and is sending us down to this short-term life as a test
to determine our worth of His Bounties to be rewarded in the REAL and ever-lasting life.
His Books ending with the Quran are our manual to pass this test.

There are many translations/interpretations of the Quran in many languages
including Arabic but none can communicate the Message of Allah fully or correctly.

However, the minimum requirements for all human beings are to:
  1. believe in one God (Creator, Life Endower, and Sustainer Who is Omnipresent, Omniscience and Omnipotent) ,
  2. believe in Judgment Day, (Responsibilities for our own actions), and
  3. do Good (to humanity and Earth for the present and future).

Quran 2:62
إِنَّ ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟ وَٱلَّذِينَ هَادُوا۟ وَٱلنَّصَٰرَىٰ وَٱلصَّٰبِـِٔينَ مَنْ ءَامَنَ بِٱللَّهِ وَٱلْيَوْمِ ٱلْـَٔاخِرِ وَعَمِلَ صَٰلِحًۭا فَلَهُمْ أَجْرُهُمْ عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ وَلَا خَوْفٌ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يَحْزَنُونَ
Lo! Those who believe (in that which is revealed unto thee, Muhammed), and those who are Jews,
and Christians, and Sabaeans - whoever believeth in Allah and the Last Day and doeth right – 
surely their reward is with their Lord, and there shall no fear come upon them neither shall they grieve.


Islamic Beliefs
---------------
  1. Oneness of God	  		التوحيد
  2. Justice of God	  		العدل
  3. Prophethood	  		النبوة
  4. Divine Leadership	  		الإمامة
  5. Resurrection	  		المعاد
	
Islamic Duties
--------------
  1. Prayer						الصلاة
  2. Fasting						الصوم
  3. Pilgrimage						الحج
  4. Income Tax (2.5%)					الزكاة
  5. Excess Tax (20%)					الخمس
  6. Fighting in the way of God				الجهاد
  7. Enjoining good					الامر بالمعروف
  8. Forbidding evil					النهي عن المنكر
  9. Supporting Ahlul-Bayt (as)				موالاة أهل البيت ع
 10. Disassociation of enemies of Ahlul-Bayt (as)	البراءة من أعداء أهل البيت ع


Ali Adams
qurancode.com
God > ∞
