Numbers are the DNA to the Universe

Mathematics may play a role in understanding the Creation process of out universe and indeed all other universes (if any).

There are hundreds of number patterns within the mathematical structure of the Book of God (Al-Quran), the outstanding of which is the Twin Numbers 114 and 506: http://heliwave.com/114_506.png

Numbers underpin the Creation process. The big bang was/is not an explosion but an ordered emission of light rays with each ray having its own serial number. That serial number determine if the light ray helicates (like a helix) clockwise or counter-clockwise [a spiral with a fixed radius f(x) = cos(x) + i sin(x)].
http://heliwave.com/Helical.Particle.Waves.pdf thanks in part to the initial idea or helical waves by the late Mr Gaasenbeek may God rest his soul in Paradise. Here are his original papers http://heliwave.com/gaasenbeek/

At the beginning there was no space, so light rays had to create space by burrowing or drilling outwards (clockwise if the serial number of the ray is composite and counter-clockwise if prime), actually the process is still going on as God says in Quran 51:47 وَٱلسَّمَآءَ بَنَيْنَٰهَا بِأَيْي۟دٍۢ وَإِنَّا لَمُوسِعُونَ
"We have indeed built the heaven with Hands and We are ever-expanding it."

Eventually, the reverse process starts when light rays lose their ability to burrow outwards and a slow but accelerating collapse will result in a big crunch as God states in Quran 21:104 يَوْمَ نَطْوِى ٱلسَّمَآءَ كَطَىِّ ٱلسِّجِلِّ لِلْكُتُبِ ۚ كَمَا بَدَأْنَآ أَوَّلَ خَلْقٍۢ نُّعِيدُهُۥ ۚ وَعْدًا عَلَيْنَآ ۚ إِنَّا كُنَّا فَٰعِلِينَ
"On a day when We will roll up the heaven the way a scriber rolls his scrolls; As We made the first creation, We repeat it. a binding promise. We indeed shall do."

Reality = Energy + Information
http://heliwave.com/Reality.html

Energy is carried by light which forms matter and antimatter while composite and prime numbers carry ALL the information required to bootstrap the Creation process at the micro-level (shared by all Universes). Then numbers specific for each Universe takeover the process (like deficient, perfect, abundant numbers and the attracting twins 114 and 506, and the repelling 12 and 21 in our base-10 or decimal Universe).
http://heliwave.com/12_21.png
http://heliwave.com/114_506.png

Yes I know I repeated the link to 114 and 506 but it is really a precious pearl found deep within the ocean of decimal numbers. It literally forces mathematics to do two things:

1. Declare even/odd numbers are merely a special case of divisibility by prime numbers (in the odd/even case divisibility by the first prime number 2).

2. Sub-classify composite and prime numbers into additive and non-additive sub-classes based on their digit sums in our decimal system. You will know what I mean when you study the http://heliwave.com/114_506.pdf :)

God has given us an Oath by the composite and prime numbers in Quran 89:1-5
وَٱلْفَجْرِ
وَلَيَالٍ عَشْرٍۢ
وَٱلشَّفْعِ وَٱلْوَتْرِ
وَٱلَّيْلِ إِذَا يَسْرِ
هَلْ فِى ذَٰلِكَ قَسَمٌۭ لِّذِى حِجْرٍ
089:001 By the Dawn, [Number 1]
089:002 by the Ten Nights, [Decimal base-10 System]
089:003 by the Dependents and Independents [Composites and the Primes]
089:004 by the Night when it departs! [Zeros between other other digits, ex: 109, 1009, 10009, ...]
089:005 Isn't this an enough Oath for those possessing intellect?

Mathematics is the language with which the Universe is being written, literally!
More number patterns within the Quran found at http://heliwave.com/114.pdf

Please watch the movie CONTACT (1997 by Carl Sagan, starred by Jodie Foster) to appreciate the Intelligent Source :)

Good luck to humanity.

Help yourself by helping others ...

Ali Adams
qurancode.com
God > ∞
